<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<item>
    <id>site:colofon</id>
    <title>Colofon</title>
    <language>en</language>
    <last-change>2007-05-10</last-change>
    <content>


<h1>Contact</h1>


<p>
Send me an email at <a href="mailto:mvermaat@cs.vu.nl" external="true">mvermaat@cs.vu.nl</a>
or <a href="mailto:martijn@vermaat.name" external="true">martijn@vermaat.name</a>.
</p>

<p>
My Jabber ID is <a href="xmpp:martijn@vermaat.name" external="true">martijn@vermaat.name</a>.
</p>


<h1>Copyright and license</h1>


<p>
All page content is, unless explicitely noted otherwise, copyright © 2004-2009
by Martijn Vermaat and licenced under a <a rel="license"
href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" external="true">Creative
Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Licence</a> (CC-BY-SA).
</p>

<p>
This means you are free to modify if you share alike, and you are free to copy
and share if you attribute me (by name, e-mail, or homepage URL).
</p>

<p>
The sourcecode of this website (with exception of all page content) is licensed
under the new <a href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php"
external="true">BSD License</a>. This translates as do whatever you like with it.
See below how to obtain said source code.
</p>


<h1>About this website</h1>


<p>
This website was constructed with maximum accessibility for the less-abled
visitor in mind. No Javascript is used, and all pages are equally usable
with or without stylesheet. Alternate stylesheets provide two high-contrast
versions of the website.
</p>

<p>
Technically, all pages should be XHTML 1.1 strict with valid CSS 2. It is
a known fact they do not have the theoretically correct mimetype. Get over
it.
</p>

<p>
The entire website is generated from some XML source files with a simple
homegrown framework based on <a href="http://ant.apache.org/"
external="true">Apache Ant</a>.
</p>


<h1>Subversion</h1>


<p>
All content and sourcecode of this website is stored in my Subversion
repository, which also hosts sources of most of my other documents and
projects.
</p>

<p>
For example, the complete sourcecode for this website can be fetched with
the command:
</p>

<pre>
$ svn export <a href="http://svn.vermaat.name/vu-website/trunk" external="true">http://svn.vermaat.name/vu-website/trunk</a> vu-website
</pre>


<h1>Sitemap</h1>


<sitemap />


    </content>
</item>
