<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<item>
    <id>site:countdown-ocaml</id>
    <title>The Countdown Problem in OCaml</title>
    <language>en</language>
    <last-change>2005-04-23</last-change>
    <content>


<h1>The game</h1>


<p>
The countdown problem is a number game from the populair quiz program
Countdown on British television.
</p>

<p>
<img src="files/countdown-ocaml/countdown.jpg" width="200" height="157"
alt="Countdown on British television" />
</p>

<p>
The essence of the problem: given a sequence of source numbers and a
single target number, construct an arithmetic expression using each
of the source numbers at most once, such that the expression evaluates
to the target number. Both the source numbers and intermediate results
must be non-zero natural numbers. The operators that can be used are
addition, subtraction, multiplication and division.
</p>

<p>
In the television version of the game, contestants do not get to use
a computer and have only 30 seconds to come up with a solution.
</p>


<h1>Functional Pearls</h1>


<p>
In an issue of the Journal of Functional Programming, Graham Hutton
published a <a href="http://www.cs.nott.ac.uk/~gmh/countdown.pdf"
external="true">Functional Pearls column on this problem</a> (pdf).
In his column, Hutton constructs a solution to the countdown problem
in Haskell, together with two simple but effective optimizations.
</p>


<h1>On the OCaml translation</h1>


<p>
A translation of Hutton's Haskell solution to OCaml is pretty straight
forward for the most part. Just like Haskell, OCaml knows pattern
matching, algebraic data types, and higher-order functions.
</p>

<p>
The main difference between the two for this problem is the lack of
list comprehensions in OCaml. This made the code more verbose and hard
to read at some places. Instead of the intuitive syntax of a list
comprehension, a lot of <code>map</code>s, <code>concat</code>s, and
<code>filter</code>s were necessary.
</p>


<h1>Download</h1>


<p>
This code is based on the work by Graham Hutton in the paper mentioned
above and available as Open Source under the new <a
href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php"
external="true">BSD License</a>.
</p>

<p>
(In other words: do with it whatever you like.)
</p>

<p>
Download <a href="files/countdown-ocaml/countdown.ml">The Countdown
Problem in OCaml</a>.
</p>


    </content>
</item>
