<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<item>
    <id>site:greasemonkey</id>
    <title>Greasemonkey User Scripts</title>
    <language>en</language>
    <last-change>2005-05-29</last-change>
    <content>


<h1>User Scripts</h1>


<p>
Below are some <a href="http://greasemonkey.mozdev.org/"
external="true">Greasemonkey</a> user scripts I wrote. Greasemonkey
is an extension for <a href="http://getfirefox.com/"
external="true">Firefox</a> which allows users to alter the content
and behavior of any website through user scripts which work inside
the browser.
</p>

<p>
For a large collection of other Greasemonkey user scripts, visit
the <a
href="http://dunck.us/collab/GreaseMonkeyUserScripts"
external="true">Greasemonkey Wiki</a>.
</p>


<h2>Installation</h2>


<p>
To install a user script, you need Greasemonkey (and for Greasemonkey,
you need <a href="http://getfirefox.com/"
external="true">Firefox</a>). After that, open the user script in
your browser, examine the source to convince yourself I'm not
stealing your passwords or anything, and select 'Install User Script'
from the 'Tools' menu in Firefox. Accept the default configuration
and go to the website the user script is written for.
</p>

<p>
After Greasemonkey is installed, a small monkey icon will appear in
the lower-right corner of Firefox. You can click on it to temporarily
disable or enable all Greasemonkey user scripts.
</p>


<h2>Editing installed scripts</h2>


<p>
To edit a user script after installation (e.g. to change some
configuration settings), locate the <code>*.user.js</code> files in
your Firefox profile directory, somewhere deep down like this:
</p>

<pre>
extensions/{e4a8a97b-f2ed-450b-b12d-ee082ba24781}/chrome/greasemonkey/content/scripts/
</pre>

<p>
Open the user script file in an editor and save it after you made
your changes. Refreshing the webpage is enough for the changes to
take effect.
</p>


<h2>License</h2>


<p>
All user scripts on this page are Open Source and licensed under the
new <a href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php"
external="true">BSD License</a>. This means you can pretty much do
with them whatever you like.
</p>


<h1>Lambda Skipper</h1>


<p>
Tracking down and reading unread posts on <a
href="http://lambda-the-ultimate.org/" external="true">Lambda the
Ultimate</a> started to annoy me quite a bit. Lambda Skipper adds
a direct jump to the top-most unread post for each node to the
<a href="http://lambda-the-ultimate.org/tracker"
external="true">Recent posts overview</a>. It also adds links to
skip to the next unread post in the node view (in top-to-bottom
order rather than chronological order).
</p>

<p>
<img src="files/greasemonkey/lambdaskipper.png" width="505" height="164"
alt="Skip to next unread post link of Lambda Skipper" />
</p>

<p>
I read Lambda The Ultimate by going to the <a
href="http://lambda-the-ultimate.org/tracker" external="true">Recent
posts overview</a> and loading all 'top-most unread post' links in
background tabs. For each tab, I go through all unread posts using
the 'next unread post' links.
</p>

<p>
<a href="files/greasemonkey/lambdaskipper-1.1.user.js">Download
Lambda Skipper 1.1</a>
</p>


<h1>Nu Compact</h1>


<p>
Nu Compact rewrites the four 'main' stories with pictures on the
<a href="http://www.nu.nl/" external="true">nu.nl</a> frontpage
to regular links. Most of the time the picture has nothing to do
with the story anyway, and this allows us to have the entire
frontpage in one screen.
</p>

<p>
<img src="files/greasemonkey/nucompact.png" width="350" height="306"
alt="Frontpage of nu.nl with Nu Compact installed" />
</p>

<p>
<a href="files/greasemonkey/nucompact-0.1.user.js">Download
Nu Compact 0.1</a>
</p>


<h1>BBTis</h1>


<p>
BBTis adds a section to your <a href="http://bb.vu.nl/"
external="true">VU Blackboard homepage</a> listing your latest
results from TisVU, so it looks something like this (except
for the striped-out grades of course):
</p>

<p>
<img src="files/greasemonkey/bbtis.png" width="548" height="420"
alt="VU Blackboard with BBTis installed" />
</p>

<p>
BBTis can be configured to automatically log in to TisVU (if
you're not already). To enable this option, locate the BBTis user
script after installation and adjust the configuration section to
your needs (as explained above).
</p>

<p>
<a href="files/greasemonkey/bbtis-1.0.user.js">Download BBTis 1.0</a>
</p>


<h1>TisNiks</h1>


<p>
TisNiks is a small collection of Javascript functions for querying
the TisVU application of the Vrije Universiteit. It is not a user
script itself, but meant to be used in user scripts.
</p>

<p>
<a href="tisniks">More about TisNiks</a>
</p>


    </content>
</item>
