<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<item>
    <id>site:greasemonkey</id>
    <title>Greasemonkey User Scripts</title>
    <language>en</language>
    <last-change>2005-05-29</last-change>
    <content>


<h1>User Scripts</h1>


<p>
Below are some <a href="http://greasemonkey.mozdev.org/"
external="true">Greasemonkey</a> user scripts I wrote. Greasemonkey
is an extension for <a href="http://getfirefox.com/"
external="true">Firefox</a> which allows users to alter the content
and behavior of any website through user scripts which work inside
the browser.
</p>

<p>
To install a user script you first need Greasemonkey installed. After
that, open the user script in Firefox and select 'Install User Script'
from the 'Tools' menu.
</p>

<p>
For a large collection of other Greasemonkey user scripts, visit
the <a
href="http://dunck.us/collab/GreaseMonkeyUserScripts"
external="true">Greasemonkey Wiki</a>.
</p>


<h2>Lambda Skipper</h2>


<p>
Tracking down and reading unread posts on <a
href="http://lambda-the-ultimate.org/" external="true">Lambda the
Ultimate</a> started to annoy me quite a bit. Lambda Skipper adds
a direct jump to the top-most unread post for each node to the
<a href="http://lambda-the-ultimate.org/tracker"
external="true">Recent posts overview</a>. It also adds links to
skip to the next unread post in the node view (in top-to-bottom
order rather than chronological order).
</p>

<p>
<a href="files/greasemonkey/lambdaskipper-1.1.user.js">Download
Lambda Skipper 1.1</a>
</p>


<h2>Nu Compact</h2>


<p>
Nu Compact rewrites the four 'main' stories with pictures on the
<a href="http://www.nu.nl/" external="true">nu.nl</a> frontpage
to regular links. The images have nothing to do with the story
anyway, and this allows us to have the entire frontpage in one
screen.
</p>

<p>
<a href="files/greasemonkey/nucompact-0.1.user.js">Download
Nu Compact 0.1</a>
</p>


<h2>TisNiks &amp; BBTis</h2>


<p>
TisNiks is a small collection of Javascript functions for querying
the TisVU application of the Vrije Universiteit. As a proof-of-concept
application of TisNiks, I created the BBTis user script that shows
your latest grades on the VU Blackboard homepage.
</p>

<p>
<a href="tisniks">More about TisNiks and BBTis</a>
</p>


    </content>
</item>
