<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<item>
    <id>site:index</id>
    <title>Home</title>
    <language>en</language>
    <last-change>2004-08-22</last-change>
    <content>


<h1>Hi</h1>


<p>
My name is Martijn Vermaat and you're looking at my personal homepage at the
Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam.
</p>

<p>
Currently, I'm a third year's student Computer Science where my main
interests are theoretical computer science and software technology. Some
additional personal information can be extracted from the Q&amp;A section
below.
</p>


<h1>On this website</h1>


<p>
What you can find on this website is the following:
</p>

<dl>
    <dt><a href="britney">Britney</a></dt>
    <dd>Britney is a simple interpreter for pure untyped Lambda Calculus,
    written in Java.</dd>
    <dt><a href="hanoi">Towers of Hanoi in Lambda Calculus</a></dt>
    <dd>A solution of the Towers of Hanoi problem in Lambda Calculus.</dd>
    <dt><a href="cddb">Exporting the Winamp CDDB database</a></dt>
    <dd>Short explanation on how to extract information from your local
    Winamp CDDB database.</dd>
    <dt><a href="vu/">VU documents</a></dt>
    <dd>All things related to my study.</dd>
    <dt><a href="links">Links</a></dt>
    <dd>Some links you might think interresting.</dd>
</dl>


<h1>Q&amp;A</h1>


<h2>Q: What kind of person are you?</h2>

<p>
A: Hmm, I dunno... you should ask me about my favourites I think.
</p>

<h2>Q: Ok, what's your favourite music?</h2>

<p>
A: Sonic Youth, Tom Waits, Neil Young, The Velvet Underground, and of
course random noise. My free tip of the day: <a
href="http://www.alizarin.nl/" external="true">Alizarin</a> (this would be
the only good music from The Netherlands I have to admit).
</p>

<h2>Q: Do you have any favourite movies?</h2>

<p>
A: Yes, but I forget them. I know American Beauty is one of them though.
</p>

<h2>Q: What's your favourite dinner?</h2>

<p>
A: That must be Tandoori Chicken. In fact, I think I'm gonna prepare some
after this interview.
</p>

<h2>Q: What's your favourite language?</h2>

<p>
A: Portuguese. 
</p>

<h2>Q: Do you speak Portuguese?</h2>

<p>
A: No.
</p>

<h2>Q: Are you on serieus medication?</h2>

<p>
A: Not that I am aware of.
</p>

<h2>Q: But don't you think it's a bit schizophrenic asking yourself these
questions?</h2>

<p>
A: No.
</p>

<h2>Q: Thank you for your time.</h2>

<p>
A: That's not a question.
</p>


    </content>
</item>
