<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<item>
    <id>site:index</id>
    <title>Home</title>
    <language>en</language>
    <last-change>2005-11-27</last-change>
    <content>


<h1>Martijn Vermaat</h1>


<p>
This is my personal homepage at the Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam where
<a href="img/martijn-southpark.png">I</a>'m a student Computer Science. My
main interests there are theoretical computer science and software technology.
</p>

<p>
As of september 2005, I'm following the master's program <a
href="http://www.cs.vu.nl/~tcs/" external="true">Formal Methods and Software
Verification</a>.
</p>

<p>
From september to december 2005, I'm practicum assistent for the course
<a href="http://www.cs.vu.nl/~tcs/il/" external="true">Inleiding Logica</a>.
(I made some <a href="vu/il-2005">notes</a>.)
</p>

<p>
Also, during spring 2006, I'm practicum assistent for the course
<a href="http://www.cs.vu.nl/~tcs/iti/" external="true">Inleiding Theoretische
Informatica</a> (<a href="vu/iti-2005">Notes for last year</a>.)
</p>


<h2>Interests</h2>


<p>
Currently I'm mostly interested in logic in computer science and the theory
and practice of programming languages (e.g. paradigms, compilers, semantics).
</p>

<p>
On a less theoretical note, I'm amusing myself playing with LaTeX (the <a
href="http://www.latex-project.org/" external="true">typesetting one</a> that
is), the <a href="http://www.debian.org/" external="true">Debian operating
system</a>, and small “never-to-finish” programming projects.
</p>

<p>
I believe in the power of free and open information and software. This includes
in particular scientific research. For some online pointers, consult my
<a href="links">Links</a> page.
</p>


<h2>Personal</h2>


<p>
Whenever there's still time left in my day, I try to spend it with my
girlfriend <a href="img/loes-southpark.png">Loes</a>, family, or friends. When
I'm alone, I try to play some
guitar (although Loes is still unimpressed by my playing skills), and listen
to music. Some of my favourite bands are <a href="http://www.sonicyouth.com/"
external="true">Sonic Youth</a>, <a href="http://www.mogwai.co.uk/"
external="true">Mogwai</a>, and my friends <a href="http://www.alizarin.nl/"
external="true">Alizarin</a> (best band of The Netherlands).
</p>


<h1>On this website</h1>


<p>
The main content of my homepage is accessible through the navigation at
the bottom of every page. All pages related to my study at university are
located in the <a href="vu/">vu</a> subdirectory.
</p>

<p>
More info about this website, including the source code, can be found on
the <a href="colofon">colofon page</a>.
</p>

<p>
If you experience problems reading these pages, please try a <a
href="http://www.apple.com/safari/" external="true">decent</a> <a
href="http://www.mozilla.org/" external="true">browser</a>.
</p>


<h1>Q &amp; A</h1>


<p>
<strong>Q:</strong> What's you favourite paradox that came as quite an
unpleasant surprise to Frege when he was just about to bring the second
volume of his Grundlagen der Arithmetik to the presses?</p>

<p>
<strong>A:</strong> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russell's_paradox"
external="true">Russell's Paradox</a>.
</p>


    </content>
</item>
