<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<item>
    <id>site:links</id>
    <title>Links</title>
    <language>en</language>
    <last-change>2006-02-16</last-change>
    <content>


<h1>Reading</h1>


<dl>

<dt><a href="http://plato.stanford.edu/" external="true">Stanford
Encyclopedia of Philosophy</a></dt>
<dd>
This free online encyclopedia of philosophy is a valuable resource.
</dd>

<dt><a href="http://lambda-the-ultimate.org/" external="true">Lambda the
Ultimate</a></dt>
<dd>
The programming languages weblog, hosts loads of interesting discussions and
links.
</dd>

<dt><a href="http://www.cs.uu.nl/~franka/ref" external="true">PLT
Online</a></dt>
<dd>
Collection of programming language theory texts and resources, all of which
are freely available over the Internet, maintained by Frank Atanassow.
</dd>

<dt><a href="http://www.lmcs-online.org/" external="true">Logical Methods in
Computer Science</a></dt>
<dd>
Free (refereed) online journal on the “theoretical and practical areas in
computer science involving logical methods, taken in a broad sense.”
</dd>

<dt><a href="http://www.godelbook.net/" external="true">Gödel's Theorems:
an Introduction</a></dt>
<dd>
This is a work in progress by Peter Smith that will become a book discussing
Gödel's incompleteness theorems and the philosophical implications. It's
accessible for undergraduates (like me).
</dd>

</dl>


<h1>Writing</h1>


<dl>

<dt><a href="http://www.phil.cam.ac.uk/teaching_staff/Smith/LaTeX/"
external="true">LaTeX for Logicians</a></dt>
<dd>
An extensive resource on the use of LaTeX for typesetting documents aimed
at logicians, but equally usefull for mathematicians and others.
</dd>

<dt><a href="http://www.bartleby.com/141/" external="true">The Elements
of Style</a></dt>
<dd>
The classic American English writing style guide by William Strunk, Jr.
</dd>

<dt><a href="http://www.chicagomanualofstyle.org/" external="true">The
Chicago Manual of Style</a></dt>
<dd>
Another well-known style guide for American English writing, focussing
more on presentational style and less on usage.
</dd>

<dt>Finally, one inline advice (taken from the excellent <a
href="http://www.haskell.org/hawiki/QuotesPage" external="true">hawiki
QuotesPage</a>):</dt>
<dd>
<pre>
&lt;shapr&gt; how will you know when you've written enough?
&lt;kosmikus&gt; I don't really know yet, but one of the following:
(a) if my supervisor tells me I have,
(b) if every chapter heading has content following it,
(c) if the deadline is there
&lt;shapr&gt; that's an excellent heuristic
</pre>
</dd>

</dl>


<h1>Listening</h1>


<dl>

<dt><a href="http://www.alizarin.nl/" external="true"
hreflang="nl">Alizarin</a></dt>
<dd>
Alizarin is a band of friends of mine that you really should check out.
</dd>

<dt><a href="http://www.luxuriamusic.com/"
external="true">LuxuriaMusic.com</a></dt>
<dd>
The only internet radio station I listen to.
</dd>

<dt><a href="http://www.sacredchao.net/quodlibet"
external="true">Quod Libet</a></dt>
<dd>
Audio player for the Gnome platform, making managing a large music collection
easy.
</dd>

</dl>



    </content>
</item>
