<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<item>
    <id>site:tisniks</id>
    <title>TisNiks</title>
    <language>en</language>
    <last-change>2005-06-04</last-change>
    <content>


<h1>About TisNiks</h1>


<p>
TisNiks is a small collection of Javascript functions for querying
the <a href="http://tisvu.vu.nl/" external="true">TisVU</a>
application. TisVU is an on-line interface for course
registration and listing exam results used at the Vrije Universiteit.
An example application using TisNiks is <a
href="tisniks#bbtis">BBTis</a>.
</p>

<p>
TisNiks is meant to be used in <a href="http://greasemonkey.mozdev.org/"
external="true">Greasemonkey</a> user scripts. It makes
use of functionality specific to Greasemonkey, therefore TisNiks
is not suitable for use outside of Greasemonkey without some
modifications.
</p>

<p>
As a proof-of-concept application of TisNiks, I created the
<a href="greasemonkey">BBTis</a> user script for Greasemonkey. It
adds a section to your <a href="http://bb.vu.nl/" external="true">VU
Blackboard homepage</a> listing your latest results from TisVU.
</p>


<h1>Using TisNiks</h1>


<p>
Currently, the way to use TisNiks in your Greasemonkey user
script is by downloading the code below and copying it to your
user script. It has only been tested with Greasemonkey 0.3.3 on
Linux.
</p>

<p>
TisNiks is Open Source and licensed under the new <a
href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php"
external="true">BSD License</a>. This means you can pretty much do
with it whatever you like.
</p>

<p>
<a href="files/tisniks/tisniks-0.2.js">Download TisNiks 0.2</a>
</p>


<h1>Development</h1>


<p>
Current features of TisNiks are just logging in and out and
querying exam results. But TisVU contains more, so TisNiks could
be extended. If you have cool ideas for TisNiks, you're welcome
to contact me and possibly get write access to the Subversion
repository containing TisNiks.
</p>

<p>
Of course, because TisNiks is free (in every sense), you can also
just take the source and extend it on your own.
</p>


    </content>
</item>
